A Guide to the Papers of Thomas R. McNamara 1967-1976
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Thomas R. McNamara Papers 1967-1976
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 4
78 Hollinger Document Cases; 34.5 linear feet
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Thomas R. McNamara, January 1976
Accession Number: A76-4
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Randolph McNamara was born in Evanston, Illinois on February 17, 1925. He has spent most of his life in Norfolk, Virginia. He was educated at Virginia Military Institute where he received a Bachelor of Science degree in Electrical Engineering (1949). He received his Bachelor of Laws degree from Washington and Lee University (1952). Mr. McNamara is married to the former Mary Bradford Colton. They have six children: Thomas Randolph, Jr.; John Colton; David Brooke; Mary Bradford; Leigh Douglas and Robert Hadley.
After returning from naval service in World War II and completing his education, Mr. McNamara joined the law firm of Williams, Cocke and Tunstall in 1952 and remained with that firm for 18 years. He practiced law on his own in Norfolk from January 1971 to January 1976 when the Virginia General Assembly elected him to a circuit judgeship in Norfolk.
Mr. McNamara's political career spanned a period of nine years. He was elected to the House of Delegates in 1967 and reelected in 1969. In 1972 he sought and won a four-year term in the Virginia Senate. In the House of Delegates his principal committee assignments were Courts of Justice (1970-1971), Counties, Cities and Towns (1968-1971) and Labor (1970-1971). His Senate Committee assignments were Agriculture, Conservation and Natural Resources; Courts of Justice; Rehabilitation and Social Services; Transportation. He also served as chairman of the Policy Advisory Committee of James River 3(c) Comprehensive Water Quality Management Study. In 1975 Governor Mills E. Godwin appointed him to the chairmanship of the State Water Control Board.
Mr. McNamara announced his intention in 1975 to return to the private practice of law in Norfolk. In January 1976, however, he was elected by the General Assembly to fill a circuit judgeship.
Mr. McNamara is a member of numerous civic and professional organizations. He is a member of the Virginia State Bar, the American, Virginia and Norfolk and Portsmouth Bar Associations; the Norfolk chapters of V.M.I. and Washington and Lee Alumni Associations; Vice-Chairman of the Lay Advisory Board, DePaul Hospital; the Board of Directors, Southeastern Tidewater Opportunities Industrialization Center, Inc.; Vice- Chairman of the Norfolk Charter Advisory Study Commission (1968-1971); chairman of the Steering Committee, Tidewater Assembly in Family Life; vice-president, Health-Welfare-Recreation Planning Council; member, Mayor's Youth Commission; Board of Directors, United Drug Abuse Council, Inc.; co-chairman, Tidewater Chapter, National Council of Christians and Jews; member, coordinating Committee on Services for the Handicapped Child of the Virginia Council on Health and Medical Care.
Scope and Content Information
The McNamara papers are principally the records of his service in the Virginia General Assembly as a member of the House of Delegates (1968-1971) and the Senate (1972-1976), annual reports of state agencies, reports of legislative study commissions and reports of the Virginia Advisory Legislative Council.
The legislative papers include a substantial number of publications of state agencies, e.g., annual reports, reports of legislative study commissions, Virginia Advisory Legislative Council reports, copies of bills and legislative correspondence. The correspondence consists of constituent letters, correspondence with officials of Tidewater area local governments and professional organizations.
The State Water Control Board files are not the official records of the board. They include Mr. McNamara's correspondence as a member of the board, staff communications, staff activities reports, letter ballots, minutes of meetings, publications distributed to members of the board and newspaper clippings related to the activities of the board.
The political papers consist of some correspondence, publications, clippings and briefs in the Virginia reapportionment cases. The speech file is principally political speeches from 1967 to 1973. The last two boxes in the collection consist of newspaper clippings.
Organization
The papers are divided into four series: Series I: Legislative Files(57 boxes); Series II: Records of Service on the State Water Control Board (15 boxes); Series III: Political Papers (4 boxes); Series IV: Newspaper Clippings (2 boxes).
Contents List
- Series I: Legislative Files
  - Sub Series A: Business Matters; Session Summaries; Miscellaneous
    - General Assembly Business Matters August-December 1968 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
    - General Assembly Business Matters 1969-1970,1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly Business Matters 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
    - General Assembly--Summary 1968 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General Assembly Session-Legislation Passed March-June, 1972 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
    - General Assembly Session--Miscellaneous February-October 1973 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General Assembly Session--Summary 1973 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
    - General Assembly Session--Miscellaneous Records 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Sub Series B: Session Summary--1975; Calendar of Events; Special Session 1969
    - General Assembly Session--Summary February-March 1975 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Assembly Manuals 1968, 1972,1974 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly: Senate Rules 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
    - General Assembly: Senate Rules Committee Reports (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
    - General Assembly: Calendar of Events 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
    - General Assembly: Special Session for Constitutional Revision 1969-1970 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
    - General Assembly: Senate Schedule, Session 1973 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Sub Series C: Bills, Bill Summaries; Model Assembly; Legislative Process
    - General Assembly:Bills 1970 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
    - General Assembly:Senate Bills and Resolutions 1972 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly:Session--Bills, January-February 1973 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
    - General Assembly: Session-House, Bill Summaries January-February 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
    - General Assembly: 1974 Session--Senate Bill Summaries January-February 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
    - General Assembly:Session--Bills Passed 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
    - General Assembly:Session--Miscellaneous Bills 1975 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
    - General Assembly: Model Assembly 1973 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
    - General Assembly: Correspondence, Other Material re Legislative Process 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sub Series D: Commission on the Legislative Process; Publicatioins
    - General Assembly: Commission on the Legislative Process--Reports 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General Assembly: Reports of Current Study Commissions-Summary February 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 2)
    - General Assembly: Publications of The Council of State Governments 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 3)
    - General Assembly: State Government News 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 4)
    - General Assembly: State Government News 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sub Series E: Legislative Correspondence,1967-1975; Legislative Material,1969-1975
    - List of Subject Headings in McNamara Files 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
    - General 1967 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
    - General January-April,1968 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
    - General May-December,1968 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
    - General 1969 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
    - General, 1970 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6)
    - General 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 7)
    - General 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous 1969-1975 (Box-folder Box 5, folder 9)
  - Sub Series F: Legislative Correspondence: Norfolk
    - City of Norfolk January 1967, 1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 1)
    - City of Norfok February 1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 2)
    - City of Norfolk March 1974-June 1975 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 3)
    - City of Norfolk--Reports of the city Assessor and the Commissioner of the Revenue 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 4)
    - City of Norfolk--Copies of Legislation Affecting City 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Norfolk, Meeting with Norfolk Delegation December 1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Norfolk, Meeting with Norfolk Delegation December 1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Norfolk Charter Bill 1970 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Sub Series G: Legislative Correspondence: Portsmouth, Virginia Beach; Proposed Programs
    - City of Portsmouth,bills prepared by Portsmouth's Commonwealth's Attorney January 1973 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 1)
    - City of Virginia Beach,includes Virginia Beach's proposals to the session of the Virginia General Assembly 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 2)
    - City of Virginia Beach includes legislative proposals of Virginia Beach 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 3)
    - City of Virginia Beach--Bond Referenda 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Beach-Norfolk Expressway renamed Robert T. Baldwin Memorial Highway 1974 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Programs Proposed by Various Organizations 1967-1972 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Programs Proposed by Various Organizations 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sub Series H: Legislative Correspondence: Virginia Municipal League
    - Virginia Municipal League Legislative Bulletin December 1972- February 1973 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Municipal League Publications 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Municipal League Meeting December 1973 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sub Series I: Legislative Correspondence; Business and Industry
    - Business and Industry--General 1967-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Business and Industry--Virginia Manufacturers Association 1969,1972 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Business and Industry--Agriculture 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Business and Industry--Antitrust and Monopoly (VALC Study) 1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Business and Industry--Banks, Savings and Loans, Credit Unions 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Business and Industry--Banking (Consumer Credit) 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Business and Industry--Banking (Credit Card Regulations) 1971-1972 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Business and Industry--Banking (Virginia Small Loan Act--VALC Report) 1967 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Construction--Mistake in bid legislation 1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Consumer Legislation 1971,1973 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Insurance (General) 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Insurance, Automobile 1975 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Insurance, Automobile(No-Fault), General 1973-1974 (Box-folder "Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Auto (No-Fault) Proposed Legislation 1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Insurance, Automobile(No-Fault) Reference Material 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Insurance(Health Insurance Regulations) March,1972 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Real Estate Regulations 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Shipping (Norfolk Port and Industrial Authority) 1967-1974 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Shipping--Va. Port Authority 1969-1974 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Sunday Closing Law March 1973-January 1974 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Sunday Closing Law February 1-13,1974 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Sunday Closing Law--February February 14-22,1974 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Sunday Closing Law March-November 1974 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Utilities(C &P Telephone) 1968,1975 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Utilities (Electricity Costs Commission)-includes Final Report of the Electricity Costs Commission 1975 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Employment Commission News January-February, 1975 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Department of Labor and Industry--Annual Report 1973 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Facts and Figures 1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 3)
    - VALC Report on Locating New Industry in Virginia 1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Industrial Facilties Financing Commission Report 1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Industrial Finance Act--Correspondence with John Bisese (Giant Markets) 1969-1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Business Index Reports 1968-1969 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Business Index Reports 1970-1973 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Employment and Housing in Virginia's Urban Corridor (VEPCO study) 1973 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Sub Series J: Legislative Correspondence: Education
    - General 1968-1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Busing 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Collective Bargaining for Teachers 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Colleges (General) 1967-1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Colleges (Council of Independent Colleges) -includes Fact Book on Private Higher Education in Virginia 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Directory of Business Schools 1967-1968 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Colleges(Virginia Foundation for Independent Colleges) 1971, 1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Colleges (Norfolk State) 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Colleges (Old Dominion University) 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Colleges, Tidewater Community College 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Colleges, University of Virginia 1969-1973 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Colleges, V.I.P. 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Colleges, Virginia State College, Dr. Filimon D. Kowtoniuk case (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Colleges, William and Mary 1963-1973 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Colleges, Program Evaluation: The Virginia Community College System--Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Colleges, State Board for Community Colleges Report 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Colleges, Financial Assistance to Attend Virginia Colleges and Universities--State Department of Education 1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 8)
    - General Assembly Commission on Higher Education, Report 1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Council of Higher Education, Miscellaneous Material 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Degrees Conferred; Resident and Extension Enrollment--State Council of Higher Education 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Financing Virginia's Colleges, Council on Higher Education 1969-1972 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Higher Education in Virginia 1971-1972; 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Virginia Plan, Council of Higher Education 1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 6)
    - The Volume and Cost of Instructional Services in Virginia's Colleges; Physical Facilities at Virginia's Colleges and Universities, Council on Higher Education 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 7)
    - State Education Assistance Authority Reports 1970-1973 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Education Commission of the States--Miscellaneous Reports 1972, 1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Norfolk Schools, General 1967-1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk Schools, Public School Officials 1968-1974 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Removal of Tolls for Students on the Elizabeth River Tunnel 1968-1972 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 5)
    - School Financing--National Education Finance Project Report 1971 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Southern Regional Education Board 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Special Education February-March, 1974 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Reports from State Department of Education 1971 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 9)
    - State Deparment of Education 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 10)
    - State Department of Education 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Superintendent of Public Instruction Annual Report 1966-1967 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Superintendent of Public Instruction--Annual Report 1967-1968 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Superintendent of Public Instruction--Annual Report 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Task Force on Financing Standards of Quality 1972 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Virginia, Commonwealth of, Reports by Various Agencies 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Congress of PTAs 1971-1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Education Association, includes VEA Research Service Reports 1967, 1970-1972 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Education Association, includes VEA Research Service Reports June 1973-August 1974 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Education Association, includes VEA Research Service reports 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Virginia School Board Association 1968, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Virginia State Advisory Council on Vocational Education, includes third, fourth and fifth annual evaluation report 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Sub Series K: Legislative Correspondence: Environment
    - General 1967-1972 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 1)
    - General 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Central Atlantic Environment Center 1972, 1974 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Citizens Against Pollution 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Conservation Council of Virginia 1974 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Critical Environment Areas, Division of State Planning 1972 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Environmental Management (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Resolution re: Environment Study Commission 1972 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Senate Bills 1972 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Agriculture 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Air Pollution, general 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Air Pollution Control, State Regulations 1972 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Air (State Air Pollution Control Board) 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Air Pollution Control, Transcript of Ohio Environmental Protection Agency Hearing 1974 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Energy Conservation 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Land Use (general), includes "Land-Use Issues" proceedings of a conference held at VPI 1974 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Land use Policies, VALC Report 1974 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Land Use: Proceedings of the Conference on Organizing and Managing the Coastal Zone (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Land Use: Critical Environmental Area, Virginia Beach January, 1974 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Legislative: Environment, land use, soil survey Master Plan 1971 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Land Use, Strip Mining (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Land Use: Wetlands Bill--Laws, Guidelines 1974 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Land Use: Wetlands Bill 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Land Use: Wetlands Bill 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Noise Abatement 1974 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Outdoor Recreation includes reports of the Commission of Outdoor Recreation 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Outdoor Recreation, the Virginia Outdoors Plan 1974 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Outdoor Recreation, Artificial Reefs 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Outdoor Recreation: Biking, Hiking Trails includes Bikeway Development Study 1973-1975 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Outdoor Recreation, Hunting and Fishing 1961, 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Outdoor Recreation, Hunting and Fishing Reducing Age for Free Licences 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Outdoor recreation, Scenic Rivers, general 1972, 1975 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Outdoor Recreation, Scenic Rivers, Rivanna River 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Pesticide Control, Virginia Pesticide Study 1971 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Pesticide Control--Economic Poisons and Ecology Reports 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Pesticide Control, Senate Bill #386 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Waste Disposal--Hampton Roads Sanitation District 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Waste Disposal, Hampton Roads Sanitation District Commission. Report on Upgrading Three Primary Plants 1972 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Waste Disposal, Hampton Roads Sanitation District Commission, Report on Interim Improvements, James River and Chesapeake Elizabeth Plants 1972 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Waste Disposal, Returnable Container Bill 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Waste Disposal, Returnable Bottle Bill 1974 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Waste Disposal, Returnable Bottle Bill, Presentation by Senator Joseph Canada 1974 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Waste Disposal, Returnable Bottles Bill, Miscellaneous Material 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Waste Disposal, Solid Wastes including Virginia Solid Waste Management Plan 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Water, Groundwater Bill 1972 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Environment: Water Resources, Groundwater of Southeastern Virginia, Division of Conservation 1972 (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Water Resources, Groundwater of Southeastern Virginia principally correspondence with Gilbert W. Francis (Box-folder Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Water Resources, Hampton Roads Channel, Craney Island 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Water Resources, Offshore Boundaries Resolution (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Water Resources, Offshore Development 1972-1975 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Water Resources, Pollution general 1971-1974 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Water Resources, Clean Water: Affluence, Influence, Effluents, NASA study 1971 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Water Resources, Pollution Control, Oil Spills 1970 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Water Resources: Pollution Control, U.S. Government Materials re Oil Spills 1970 (Box-folder Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Water Resources: Water Resources Development in Virginia, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers 1973 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Water Resources: Virginia Institute of Marine Science, general 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Water Resources: Virginia Institute of Marine Science, News Releases and Wave Climate Model of the Mid-Atlantic Shoreline, Virginia Sea, NASA study (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Water Resources: Virginia Marine Resources Commission Report 1973 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Water Resources: State Water Control Board, general 1971-1973 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Water Resources: State Water Control Board, general 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Water Resources: Correspondence re: State Water Control Board 1967, 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Water Resources: State Water Control Board First Annual Report 1972-1973 (Box-folder Box 25, Folder 8)